Muhammad Naufal Pratama

muhammadnaufalp@students.undip.ac.id \cdot +62 82133617483 \cdot LinkedIn \cdot Github \cdot Medium

A highly passionate person in the technology field with a bunch of experience in software engineering, especially on the BackEnd side, with the extra ability of System Programming and DevOps-related stuff.

EXPERIENCES

C++ Software Engineer Intern

Nodeflux

Internship

August 2022 - December 2022

- Dealing against C++ in an internship as a C++ SWE intern at Nodeflux. Develop two different surveillance camera analytic products that runs on top of Docker and implement a dynamically loaded library in C++.
- Tech: C++, Python, ONNX, Vegeta & Hey, Grafana, Prometheus, Docker & Postman

DevOps/SRE Intern

Fita

Internship

June 2022 - August 2022

- Having internship as the DevOps/SRE intern at Fita (Telkomsel's subsidiary) and Contribute to the GCP cloud armor setup and the Helm configuration, create a dependency auto updater pipeline using Renovate, and finish with a VictoriaMetrics alert setup..
- Tech: GitLab CI/CD, GCP, Kubernetes and Helm, Terraform & Grafana

Generasi GIGIH 2.0

Studi Independen Kampus Merdeka

Backend Engineer Course

Feb 2022 - July 2022

- Participate as a Backend Engineer and gain a lot of insight in Generasi GIGIH 2.0 program held by Yayasan Anak Bangsa Bisa, (YABB) and developing a trash delivery system as the final project.
- Tech: Ruby, Ruby On Rails & Git

Fullstack Engineer Intern

Internship

UPT Perpustakaan UNDIP Feb 2022 - June 2022

- Work eagerly as a full-stack engineer to develop an automated mail template platform for helping library staff write an office letter without manually writing it through a word editor.
- Tech: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP, Laravel, Redis, RabbitMQ, Git & Heroku

IEEE SB-Undip Organization

 $Web\ Division\ Committe$

Universitas Diponegoro July 2021 - May 2022

- Initiate and manage IEEE SB-Undip the website using WordPress and coordinate website development training the IWT (IEEE Website Training).
- Tech: Wordpress

Software Defect Prediction Research

 $University\ Research$

Universitas Diponegoro March 2021 - October 2021

- Research and explore in-depth defects in software using machine learning and deep learning algorithms such as CNN, LSTM, and Random Forest from the experiments until the journal publications.
- Tech: Python, Keras, NumPy, Git, Machine learning & Deep learning

Backend Engineer Mulo

Part-time Backend Engineer

Mulo, Wonosobo Feb 2021 - Aug 2022

- Contribute in both the backend API and also the android app for Mulo, which is a startup company focusing on empowering UMKM in Indonesia by providing an application that can help manage UMKM activities and finances using blockchain technology.
- Tech: NodeJS, SailsJS, Kotlin, PostgreSql, Insomnia, Git & Heroku

Backend Engineer Intern

Internship

Azura Labs, Semarang Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

- Develop backend REST API using Laravel for a web-based project called 'Butiko', which contains articles and activities carried out by the 'Butiko' community.
- Tech: PHP, Laravel, MySql, Insomnia & Git

EDUCATION

Universitas Diponegoro

Semarang, Jawa Tengah 2019 - August 2023 (Expected)

Majoring in **Informatics** *GPA*: 3.82 out of 4.00 Taking a specialization in software engineering

Projects

COBLOS Laravel, Bootstrap, Git

COBLOS

Contribute as the backend programmer in developing a survey web-based application that helps companies or individuals manage their surveys.

Siperpus Laravel, SailsJS, Bootstrap, Git

sisperpus | API

Give an extraordinary contribution as the backend programmer for this project and great teamwork. Siperpus is a library management system developed using Laravel.

Anforom 2021 Laravel, JavaScript, Github

Anforcom

Took charge as a backend programmer in creating, developing, and maintaining Anforcom's website, which is a competition and seminar that is held annually by the HMIF Undip.

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Fresh Graduate Academy Game Programming

Agate International June 2022

New experience learning about the basics of game programming from theory to hands-on implementation.

Text Retrieval and Search Engines University of Illinois offered through Coursera *Aug 2021* Digest knowledge about information and text retrieval and grasp how a search engine works.

Cyber Security Essential

Cisco Networking Academy Feb 2020

Having a good understanding on the tactics, techniques, and procedures used by cyber criminals in cyber security world.

SKILLS

Hard Skills: C++, Rust, Python, PHP, JavaScript, SQL, Laravel, NodeJS, Postman, Heroku, Redis,

RabbitMQ, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, GitLab CI/CD, Grafana,

Prometheus, ONNX, CMake, Vegeta.

Soft Skills: Analytical & critical thinking and time management.